<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Plugins on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/plugins/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Plugins on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/plugins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ IDEA as a LaTeX editor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/intellij-latex-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/intellij-latex-editor/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: IntelliJ Idea is great for working with LaTeX. The basic functionality is provided by plugins, and a lot of additional automation can be set using File Watchers. I only miss displaying chapters and sections like in TexStudio.&#xA;LaTeX in IntelliJ IDEA I don&amp;rsquo;t work with LaTeX very often, but this format has many advantages, especially when working on longer written forms, containing a lot of graphics, diagrams, mathematical formulas, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IntelliJ settings repo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/intellij-settings-repo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/intellij-settings-repo/</guid>
      <description>My setup looks like this: I have Windows PC with Linux installed on a separate drive, also I have 2 MacBooks for work, and rarely used Linux ThinkPad. Keeping my IntelliJ settings in sync at all of those machines wasn&amp;rsquo;t really possible. If I find some setting that improves my workflow at my office machine, and after some time I want to work on a pet project on my own PC - I get this itch of not having this setting I had on MacBook&amp;hellip; so I can export my settings and then import it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nyan your terminal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/nyan-your-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 08:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/nyan-your-terminal/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer #1: I&amp;rsquo;m an Android developer, not sysadmin. I use terminal to help me with my workflow, not as my main tool, so please keep this in mind :)&#xA;Disclaimer #2: This is based on Linux (Ubuntu), but most stuff should work on OSX also.&#xA;Terminal? If you are a developer (and not a Windows peasant), you might had to use terminal for day to day stuff like installing node.js or python packages, or running scripts.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
