<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software Development on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/software-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software Development on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/software-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Android Presentation Patterns: MVI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024-02-24-MVI/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024-02-24-MVI/</guid>
      <description>MVI isn&amp;rsquo;t a single ready-to-implement pattern; it&amp;rsquo;s more of a spectrum. This post delves into its diverse range, from basic MVVM patterns to intricate Redux-like state management, emphasizing the importance of grasping its principles for effective implementation tailored to specific project needs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android Presentation Patterns: MVVM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024-02-09-MVVM/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024-02-09-MVVM/</guid>
      <description>Evolution There is a clear trajectory in presentation pattern evolution - decreased coupling. In MVC, components were closely situated, with numerous direct interactions. MVP addressed this by introducing a standard interface structure. It&amp;rsquo;s now possible to test some interactions without relying on UI (although it may sound somewhat peculiar when discussing presentation patterns, I admit). Nevertheless, there are still some challenges, such as maintaining view state or artificial awareness of view lifecycle in MVP.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Android Presentation Patterns: MVP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024-01-29-MVP/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024-01-29-MVP/</guid>
      <description>But MVC does the job! When examining the MVC pattern as described here, it&amp;rsquo;s evident that the direct relationship between the View and Controller is problematic. Tight coupling results in challenging testing, where changes in one class necessitate updates in another, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale well. In complex views, there can be multiple conditions for setting values in UI elements, depending on the current state of the UI and responses from the Model.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Integration and Deployment: A Developer&#39;s Best Friends</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023-06-16-ci-is-your-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023-06-16-ci-is-your-friend/</guid>
      <description>Intro In today&amp;rsquo;s fast-paced software development landscape, Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) have become indispensable tools for developers. If you are already familiar with this concept, this post may not be for you. However, if you&amp;rsquo;re new to CI/CD and want to learn what it is, how to set it up, and why it&amp;rsquo;s cool, you&amp;rsquo;re in the right place. CI/CD can eliminate some manual labor, streamline workflows, and make your development process more efficient and reliable.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
